♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 17]
I didn't set the fire in Shijia Town.
Still, he is the survivor.
Fan Xian is still investigating
your past deal with Northern Qi.
All the more reason not to kill him.
The Imperial Inspectorate surely knows
about this by now as you do.
Let him investigate.
I'm also curious about
who set that fire.
Where is that person?
Tongfu Inn.
The First Division
secretly surrounded the place
to prevent any sinister move.
Deng Ziyue is thoughtful.
Hold on.
What's the name of the inn again?
Tongfu Inn.
What's the surname of the innkeeper?
If it's Tongfu Inn,
it should be Tong.
Is it a man or a woman?
Maybe a man.
Mr. Fan, if you want a woman,
I will get one for you.
Scratch that.
I didn't ask for anything.
You,
leave now.
Godfather.
Shut up.
Scholars must have a backbone.
Godfather, I...
Don't be a shameless social climber.
He Zongwei,
I'm kind enough
not to chuck you out.
Educated men can't bend their knees,
nor should they.
I truly admire you, Godfather...
Get lost!
Godfather,
I shall take my leave.
He came here to offer
his service to you.
I still have some pride.
I won't take in someone like him.
Hopefully, educated men
won't demean themselves like he does.
He is one in a million.
Youngsters are mostly with pride.
I hope so.
Wang,
let's go to the Tongfu Inn later.
We are meeting the only survivor.
Whether or not the aggrieved souls
of the Shijia Town can rest in peace
depends on him.
Educated men can't bend their knees,
nor should they.
What a fighting talk.
But standing upright isn't easy.
Yogurt for sale!
Delicious yogurt!
Please stop here.
Until next time.
Safe trip.
You are here, Mr. Fan.
May I have a word?
Mr. Fan.
Does Shi Chanli stay here?
Yes, in a quad room.
The other three tenants
are also candidates.
Here are their names.
[Roommates]
Yang Wanli, Cheng Jialin, Hou Jichang.
We are investigating
their family backgrounds.
The results will be out soon.
Besides, sir,
this is a detailed record of Shi Chanli's activity
since he checked into the inn.
Please review it.
You even investigated this.
It's always good to be well-prepared.
In case you need it.
[Shi Chanli]
He even drank?
He had a joyful conversation
with the other three
and had a few drinks.
He is not a good drinker.
He is not in the inn now?
Yes.
He is in the exam hall.
There are still a few days
until the exam.
What is he doing there?
He is building walls.
Building walls?
Be careful.
Gently.
Slowly.
All right.
Mr. Fan, please look.
They are the candidates
for the coming spring exam.
What are they doing?
They are helping the Ministry of Rites
to renovate the exam hall.
Renovate the exam hall?
Isn't this the builders' work?
Why are these candidates doing that?
Yes.
The Minister of Rites,
Mr. Guo Zheng, suggested this.
He said there are many candidates
who come
from different family backgrounds.
Plus, the cost of living
in the Capital is high,
which might be a burden
for students of humble roots.
So it's better to pay the money
to these students
than the builders.
Exactly.
It's voluntary.
They can feel the grandness
of the exam hall in advance
and earn some money
to make a living.
By the look of it,
this minister
does take pity on the people.
Mr. Fan, that's Mr. Guo.
Mr. Guo would rather
get his hands dirty.
But why isn't he moving?
Get stuck there?
Here's a painter.
Indeed.
The renovation of the exam hall
is considered quite a contribution.
Naturally, he would want
to record this moment.
Some of the officials
have this preference.
Interesting.
Why don't we get a portrait
after we go back to the First Division?
Where is Shi Chanli?
Mr. Fan, he is over there.
Is he striking a pose too?
But there isn't any painter around.
The guards are not strict, though.
The guards are protecting the minister.
No one cares about these candidates.
We need two more people here.
He Zongwei.
Do you want to become an official?
Will you take the risk
for a chance to succeed?
May I know who you are?
Be careful, everyone.
Shi.
Who are you?
Shi, you forgot me.
We met before.
Did we?
Shi, are you staying in the Tongfu Inn?
Yes.
In a quad room?
That's right.
You come from Shijia Town on the border.
How did you know everything?
You told me.
Did I?
We chatted a little over some drinks
that night.
Were you there?
We were in the loo.
I was drunk that night.
I couldn't remember.
Shi, are you short of money?
Well, kind of.
Takes one to know one.
I'm Hou Jichang.
[Hou Jichang, candidate in the spring exam]
Let me find your name.
Hey, Shi.
Is he your friend?
I also stay in Tongfu Inn.
We met before.
Shi, why don't you introduce us
to one another?
This is my roommate, Hou.
Hou Jichang.
Hi, Hou. My surname is Fan.
Fan?
Hi, Fan.
We are fated
since we stay in the same inn.
Did I interrupt you?
Not at all.
Just now,
I saw you holding a brick
and zoning out.
What's wrong?
I saw that too.
Shi,
[Shi Chanli]
did you forget what I told you?
I saw you sitting there
and staring at the two bricks
from a distance.
Mr. Guo is monitoring the site.
Even if you are tired,
you have to pretend to be hardworking.
I'm not tired.
I just found these bricks strange.
What's strange about the bricks?
Let me show you.
This
is the old brick,
and this
is the new replacement brick.
So?
The new brick.
The old brick.
Can you tell from the sounds?
The old brick sounds like an iron.
Iron?
This is the best kiln brick.
Kiln bricks are extremely expensive.
However, the replacement bricks
are very ordinary bricks.
Look at this too.
The pillars taken down
are Phoebe Zhennan.
Look at the replacement pillars.
Do you know what these are?
They are just logs.
They are ordinary.
Too ordinary.
That's why I'm confused.
Why are they using
a more inferior material
for the renovation of the exam hall?
Shi, how do you know about these things?
I run a business back in my hometown,
so I have some knowledge of this.
I'm sure about this.
Shi.
Don't mention this ever again.
Why not?
Mr. Guo supervises
the renovation personally.
All the more reason to inform Mr. Guo,
so that he won't be shortchanged.
This is none of our business.
We had better
ignore this.
But...
Trust me.
Why ignore?
Substituting with poor materials
is a corrupt behavior.
We well-educated men
should be sensible and ethical.
Why could we ignore this?
Lower your voice.
Please don't mind them.
They are always like this.
Even if you can cover my mouth,
you can't cover others'...
I beg of you.
Let me finish first.
Fan, please have some water.
Sure, thank you.
Let me introduce him to you.
This is Yang Wanli from Quanzhou.
He is quite famous in his hometown.
He is the top graduate
in the provincial exam.
Among the four of us,
Yang is the most knowledgeable.
Nice to meet you, Yang.
Likewise.
I will go and sound the yamen's drum...
Being book-smart isn't enough.
Even if you want to report corruption,
who will believe
people like us?
I heard that Mr. Fan
is...
Do you even know him?
I can try to get to know him.
Does Mr. Guo know Mr. Fan?
Of course.
Who among you two is closer to Mr. Fan?
Mr. Guo.
They preside over
the spring exam together.
What if
they came to a consensus on this?
[Yang Wanli, candidate of the spring exam]
I see what you mean.
You are saying
that Mr. Fan and Mr. Guo
are in cahoots...
I didn't mean that.
What did you mean, then?
What I'm trying to say is,
put up with that.
Don't ever bring this up again.
If I were to tolerate this,
what's the point of studying?
If you want to intervene with this,
now is not the time.
When?
Yang, let me ask you.
Why did we come to the Capital?
To become officials.
Then, why are we working
on the renovation here?
To become officials.
If so, are you an official now?
No.
If you want to intervene,
tolerate it until we gain power.
Do educated men really
have to endure this?
This is the norm.
I will take my leave.
Yang.
How come a scholar
is so reckless?
Hou,
just now,
you said everyone came here
because they want to become officials.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
Life is hard.
We are just making a living here.
Besides money,
Hou also told us more
about this renovation work.
Shi.
Don't worry.
Shi...
We are candidates.
We should share.
Hou said
we came here to work
not only for money,
but also to show our faces.
Show our faces?
Candidates who came here
have their names registered.
Mr. Guo is here on the site.
It would be best
if he could remember our names.
Remember our names?
Fan, you see.
There are so many candidates.
If our names could be remembered,
we could leave him
with a good impression.
Maybe he might take an extra look
when he reviews our exam papers.
Hou, you are thinking ahead.
Otherwise, people like us
wouldn't be able to pass the exam.
Isn't the spring exam
assessing our knowledge?
Knowledge is useless
if we come from a humble background.
How is that related to one's background?
Mr. Fan, let me tell you this.
Candidates in the spring exam every year
are too many to count.
However, there are only limited quotas
for each department.
There are rumors circulating
that the court officials,
someone from the palace,
and the imperial academy
would select some candidates
and famous scholars.
Consequently,
there aren't many spots left.
How come they begin to select candidates
even before the exam?
People who are of means
and with backgrounds
would seek apprenticeships
and offer their services to dignitaries.
Seeing as they would eventually
become peers in court,
those dignitaries would undoubtedly
help their own disciples.
What's the point of all that?
Candidates will only be evaluated
by their knowledge.
Obtaining special favors
is more effective
than having a knowledgeable mind.
From what you said,
this spring exam
is held for the court officials
to choose lackeys.
Yang, mind your mouth.
You might lose your life
for saying that.
Fan,
don't take it too seriously.
Don't get yourself in trouble.
Selecting candidates before the exam
and using the exam as a smokescreen.
Isn't this cheating?
That's right.
Not so loud.
I'm wondering
if this is true,
why hasn't anyone exposed
this situation?
Expose whom?
The justice court
is also run by officials.
Where is fairness?
What did you say?
Fairness.
There is no such thing.
Without fairness,
isn't this spring exam
a laughable joke?
Perhaps
we could change this
when we succeed.
Where is Cheng Jialin?
He is breaking stones in the backyard.
I told him
to keep his mouth shut.
Now I think of it,
this is truly meaningless.
I'm back to work.
Shi.
Be discreet.
Fan.
Can you do me a favor?
Hou Jichang.
You are so well done!
You have carried so many logs
by yourself.
It's my duty.
Good work.
Do you want to take a rest?
You haven't had any water
since this morning.
It's fine.
It's my duty.
Are you sure?
Let me give you a hand.
That's enough.
Enough.
Enough?
Yes.
Sure?
Should I give a few more shouts?
No need. That's enough.
Fan,
here you go.
- Eat some flatbread.
- No, thanks.
Eat this.
Keep it for yourself.
Well, I will buy your drinks
the other day.
Sure thing.
Thank you.
Mr. Fan?
Do you recognize me, Mr. Guo?
I have seen your brilliant debate
in the court before.
Uh...
You are the chief examiner this time,
Mr. Guo.
Please don't be so courteous.
[Guo Zheng, Minister of Rites]
Mr. Fan, you are a great prospect.
I know you will go places in the future.
Mr. Fan,
what brings you to the exam hall?
I swing by to visit you.
I have been meaning to meet you.
Please have a seat.
There is no need for that.
Mr. Guo,
may I ask you a question?
Please.
Using poor-quality replacement materials
in the renovation of the exam hall,
are you aware of this?
They are not that bad.
The materials are durable.
In that case, you are aware of this.
If I said I didn't,
wouldn't it be absurd?
Does the Ministry of Revenue
allocate funds for the renovation?
Of course.
We wouldn't dare renovate the premises
without the funds.
Since you are installing
more "durable" materials,
how much money is left?
I believe there are remaining.
Those kiln bricks
and Phoebe Zhennan pillars
are valuable.
They are stored
in the Ministry of Rites' warehouse.
The remaining money is also
recorded in the ledger.
I know you have a lofty ambition.
You vow to fight
against corruption and evil.
I commend you on that.
So I won't overstep your line.
Not a single dime
of this renovation project
has come into my pocket.
My conscience is clear.
If you don't believe me,
feel free to investigate.
The Ministry of Rites
will cooperate fully.
The money is recorded in the ledger?
Fully recorded.
The materials are in the warehouse.
None are missing.
I'm confused.
What are you after
for doing this?
As the Minister of Rites,
I mustn't sit on my hands.
We officials
should do practical things.
Point taken.
The renovation is a practical thing.
It's considered
the political performance.
Political performance?
That's a wise choice of words.
I haven't heard it before.
Political performance.
You even drew yourself a portrait.
It's proof of my contribution.
It will remind me of what I have done.
What about the remaining money?
There are many officials
in the Ministry of Rites.
It's difficult for them
to provide for the family.
Besides, they need money
to buy liquor and meat
during festivals.
Don't you think so?
What about the material
in the warehouse?
We are clean officials.
Some officials might need to repair
their run-down houses.
With the materials in the warehouse.
It's not against the rules.
It's not illegal.
This isn't against the rules.
Absolutely.
Mr. Guo, you have been
in office for years.
You have the court's rules
wrapped around your finger.
I'm clean,
but I need to take care of myself.
Aren't you afraid
that those candidates might find out?
It's no use even if they do.
If someone succeeds in the exam
and impeaches you,
it will be troublesome.
Mr. Fan, like I said,
nothing I do is against the rules.
Besides, these people out there
won't make it through the exam.
What do you mean?
In the coming spring exam,
names on this list
[Record of Spring Exam Hall Renovation]
will be disqualified.
Why is that so?
These candidates
are cunning.
Why did they come here to work?
All they want is
to impress me.
How could we admit
opportunistic candidates like them?
Even though they didn't do anything yet?
Literary men must
have a noble character,
like me.
I can't tolerate shameless fawners.
Is any of these candidates
your retainer?
I just don't want
to go hard on them.
Mr. Fan, one's character
is all that matters.
Look at me.
I unconditionally believe in
your character.
No matter what your intention is,
I won't oppose it.
Have it your way.
Hou Jichang.
You are so capable.
Indeed, Hou Jichang.
You are so hardworking.
It's my duty.
You are so amazing, Hou Jichang.
You have been carrying the logs
a thousand times, right?
Well done, Hou Jichang!
Hou Jichang, great work!
Let's change to another side.
The accommodation fee in the Capital
is too hefty for the candidates.
Poor candidates
have to find a way to make money.
So many of them.
Exactly.
Potential literary men across the world
have gathered in the Capital.
That candidate is quite of age.
I bet he has taken the exam
several times.
He must come here bearing hopes
every time.
Only a few will be selected
from a large pool of candidates.
Not everyone can have the chance.
What does the spring exam mean
to them?
It's the grace from the state.
What else?
As you said,
it's an opportunity
to change their destiny.
Right.
They study hard for years
for this very opportunity.
This is supposed
to be a fair opportunity.
Have you heard about
the spring exam corruption?
Look, the pigeon is plumpy.
It must be from the Imperial Inspectorate.
I doubt it flies the long route.
I... I didn't have anything now.
Otherwise, I would...
Don't deflect.
I was just asking casually.
You can answer it casually.
If so, I will answer it casually.
Before the spring exam begins,
many candidates have already
sought apprenticeships
and offered their services
to dignitaries.
This sorry bunch
secured a guaranteed future
even before the exam.
The exam hall
is merely a smokescreen.
What about them?
They weren't born
with such privileges.
Does the Imperial Inspectorate
not know about this?
They know a thing or two.
Their duty is to monitor the officials.
Why didn't they look into this?
Only big shots
take in disciples.
They are too difficult and influential
to be investigated.
This unwritten rule
has been perpetuated for years.
Everyone got used to that.
But to them,
this is
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
There are some quotas allocated
for the candidates in the exam hall.
This is just not fair.
What is the name of the inn again?
Tongfu.
Did Fan Xian go there?
Yes.
But the man wasn't there.
So he headed to the exam hall.
To find that Shi what?
Shi Chanli.
He met him,
but they didn't talk much.
Our men watched them from a distance.
They said Shi Chanli didn't look sad.
He probably didn't know
about the massacre in Shijia Town.
He didn't tell him anything?
Then, why did he go there?
Yes, why?
What a wasted trip.
I wonder
what is on Fan Xian's mind.
Mr. Fan,
what are you thinking?
Nothing, really.
The spring exam is in a few days.
I wonder how Shi Chanli
would handle the exam
if he knew what happened
in his hometown.
Let's wait.
The First Division is watching him.
We will see what to do
after he finishes the exam smoothly.
Mr. Fan,
you are really different.
How so?
Other officials
couldn't care less about these people.
At least, we should treat them
with the slightest respect.
[Fan's Residence]
Have we reached home?
You should look at this.
This is for Mr. Fan.
Just a little gift. Please accept it.
Isn't that Xin Qiwu?
It's him.
Some of them also look familiar.
I saw them in the court.
They are in casual clothes now.
It would be inconvenient
if they wore the official robes.
I left a message
inside it.
I shall leave.
Mr. Fan doesn't take gifts.
No gifts.
It's true. Please take it back.
Coming through.
We don't accept gifts.
He is coming this way.
Please stop giving us the gifts.
We are just servants.
Please stop.
I shall take my leave.
I will put them here.
Please pass them on to Mr. Fan.
It's because of the spring exam?
Apparently.
Come, let's use the back door.
Your Highness,
it doesn't feel right.
How come no one is spotted
in the Fan's Residence?
Because we came in
through the back door.
But this is simply empty.
Do you know why it's empty?
Because
the Fan Residence is in trouble?
Because we haven't been here before.
Where is Fan Xian's courtyard?
Shall we search around?
Put them here.
Go back the same way we came.
Wait for me outside.
It's rotating.
Master,
the Crown Prince came.
Why did you dismiss all the servants?
Did he use the back door?
It doesn't matter which door he used,
he is the Crown Prince.
Now that
you have dismissed the servants,
shouldn't you go and meet him?
He isn't here for me.
I can't go.
Do you know how to navigate
with the volatile officialdom?
How?
Stand steady.
Just mind our own business.
It's better to stay out
of things unrelated to us.
Master,
why did the Crown Prince
come here personally
for Fan Xian?
What else could it be?
The spring exam is around the corner.
He came to give a heads-up.
But why did he use the back door?
Figure this out yourself.
It's not moving.
My goodness.
Your Highness, why did you dismantle it?
I'm sorry, Fan.
It wasn't moving just now,
so I was thinking of fixing it a bit.
Perhaps
I did it too much.
Well,
how much is this? I will pay you back.
I was joking.
Please get out of the water.
All right.
What brings you here, Your Highness?
Do you want to listen
to the truth or the lie?
I'm fine with either of them.
I came here to talk you out.
Of what?
Because of your fallout with Chengze,
he is grounded for six months.
I feel bad for my own brother.
That's why I must come to advise you.
This is a lie.
Apparently.
What about the truth?
Speaking of the truth...
I'm coming.
Did anyone call him?
As long as he believes so.
The truth is
you upset Chengze,
which made me thrilled.
So I brought some gifts to you.
Your Highness, you surely
didn't see me as an outsider.
You and Chengze are fighting each other.
Of course we are on the same side.
But I don't know what you like.
These are valuables, jewels,
and precious herbs.
I prepared some of everything.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I like them all.
Good that you are frank.
I suppose you didn't come here
only to send gifts, Your Highness.
Well, that's the main reason.
Main reason?
I also have some trivial matters.
How trivial is it?
Just some trivial names.
You are in charge
of the anonymous transcription, right?
[Song Changning, Wei Sinan, Sheng Huaiyuan]
Pay attention to these names.
What do you want me to do,
Your Highness?
You don't have to do anything.
Do nothing
during the anonymous transcription.
That's all I need.
Well, there's nothing else.
I should get going.
Initially,
my men were supposed
to send these gifts over.
But then, I thought
we were on the same side.
Also, I missed you,
so I came here myself
to show my sincerity.
You truly are sincere, Your Highness.
There is a survivor in Shijia Town.
You heard about that too?
It concerns Chengze's smuggling.
Naturally, I will pay attention to that.
Is anything worth mentioning?
He is a candidate.
I haven't told him anything yet.
I will wait until the exam is over.
As you say.
I'm leaving.
No need to see me off.
I will find my way out.
Just go in the opposite direction
of the arrow.
Mr. Fan,
here's a letter from Prime Minister Lin.
He sends for you.
[Yuan Hongdao,
counselor of Prime Minister Lin]
Sir,
is this name all right?
Yes.
Mr. Lin.
Do away with formalities.
Come here
and help me.
Lately,
my beard has grown
quite a few white hairs.
Right, there are.
Pull them out for me.
Me?
I can't do this myself.
It hurts.
Come again.
Quick.
One more time.
Pull it off.
No...
Stop here.
Mr. Lin,
I don't think it's that painful.
I can't bear the pain. I'm scared.
Why don't you just trim them?
They still grow.
It doesn't solve the problem.
Let's stop here for today.
Sir,
his background is clean.
All right.
[Huan Xianzhong
of Heinan Circuit in Xuzhou]
Fan Xian.
Look.
My beard
is neat, right?
Refined.
Good.
Being an official is similar to
how we comport ourselves.
Be mindful
of small details.
Most importantly,
don't expose anything
that will give yourself away.
Mr. Lin, what is this?
Dabao likes eating hawthorns.
I'm picking good ones for him.
He always eats eagerly.
I'm afraid he might choke on the seeds.
Mr. Fan,
he won't let servants
do this.
Did the Crown Prince come to you?
Word spreads fast.
Did he give you a name list?
Yes.
He asked me not to do anything
during the anonymous transcription.
Indeed, you don't have to do anything.
Someone will handle it.
You only need to turn a blind eye.
To what?
What else could it be?
Let them put the names
of the selected ones
on the honor roll.
[Spring Metropolitan Exam]
[Yun Heshun of Heinan Circuit
in Laizhou, No. 13 of East]
[No. 13 of East]
[Examiner Sealer's seal]
Pick the chosen candidates out
during the procedure?
These people will definitely
make it onto the honor roll.
What if their essays
aren't well-written?
Won't anyone suspect that?
There is always a way.
That's why your position
is very crucial.
Do you know
how many name lists
those officials and dignitaries will send to you?
I do.
People have been sending gifts
these days.
They didn't leave their names,
but there is a note
behind each gift box.
Pay no mind to those.
The important names
are all here.
Why do you have them?
I intercepted the gifts
and had Mr. Yuan filter out the names.
The list is shorter now.
Just remember these names.
Isn't this the spring exam?
Shouldn't they pass the exam
by their merit?
These aren't just names.
This is how
the bureaucratic world works.
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪